<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<MOSTROS>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Ettercap</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>NE</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>13</AC>
        <HP>44 (8d8+8)</HP>
        <SPEED>30 ft., climb 30 ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Medium.</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>1.80 mts.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>90 kg.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>14</STR>
        <STRMOD>+2</STRMOD>
        <DEX>15</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+2</DEXMOD>
        <CON>13</CON>
        <CONMOD>+1</CONMOD>
        <INT>7</INT>
        <INTMOD> -2</INTMOD>
        <WIS>12</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+1</WISMOD>
        <CHR>8</CHR>
        <CHRMOD> -1</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>Perception +3; Stealth +4; Survival +3.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>Darkvision 60 ft.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>2 (450 XP)</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Spider Climb. The ettercap can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Web Sense. While in contact with a web, the ettercap knows the exact location of any other creature in contact with the same web.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>Web Walker. The ettercap ignores movement restrictions caused by webbing.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Multiattack. The ettercap makes two attacks: one with its bite and one with its claws.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>4</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Bite. Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: (1d8 + 2) piercing damage plus (1d8)poison damage. The target must succeed on a DC 11 Constitution saving throw or be poisoned for 1 minute. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>2</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>8</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>2</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Claws. Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: (2d4 + 2) slashing damage. </ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>2</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>4</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>2</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>    Web (Recharge 5-6). Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 30/60 ft., one large or smaller creature. The creature is restrained by webbing. As an action, the restrained creature can make a DC 11 Strength check, escaping from the webbing on a success. The effect also ends if the webbing is destroyed. The webbing has AC 10, 5 hit points, vulnerability to fire damage, and immunity to bludgeoning, poison, and psychic damage.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Aarakocra</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>NG</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>12</AC>
        <HP>13 (3d8).</HP>
        <SPEED>20ft. fly 50ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Medium.</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>1.5 m.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>45k.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>10</STR>
        <STRMOD>0</STRMOD>
        <DEX>14</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+2</DEXMOD>
        <CON>10</CON>
        <CONMOD>0</CONMOD>
        <INT>11</INT>
        <INTMOD>0</INTMOD>
        <WIS>12</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+1</WISMOD>
        <CHR>11</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>0</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>passive Perception 15</SKILL>
        <SENSES>.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>1/4 (50XP).</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Dive Attack. If the aarakocra is flying and dives at leas t 30 feet straight toward a target and then hits it with a melee weapon attack, the attack dea ls an extra 3 (1d6) damage to the target.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>4</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Talon. Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4  (1d4 + 2) slashing damage.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>1</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>4</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>2</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Javelin. Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>1</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>6</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>2</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Aboleth</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>LE</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>17</AC>
        <HP>135 (18d10+36).</HP>
        <SPEED>10ft. swim 40ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Large.</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>6.1m</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>2900k.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>21</STR>
        <STRMOD>+5</STRMOD>
        <DEX>9</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>-1 </DEXMOD>
        <CON>15</CON>
        <CONMOD>+2</CONMOD>
        <INT>18</INT>
        <INTMOD>+4</INTMOD>
        <WIS>15</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+2</WISMOD>
        <CHR>18</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>+4</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>History +12, Perception +10</SKILL>
        <SENSES>darkvision 120ft., passive Perception 20. Telepathy 120ft.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>10 (5.900XP)</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Amphibious. The aboleth can breathe air and water.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Mucous Cloud. While underwater, the aboleth is surrounded by transformative mucus. A creature that touches the aboleth or that hits it with a melee attack while within 5 feet of it must make a DC 14 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the creature is diseased for 1d4 hours. The diseased creature can breathe only underwater.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>Probing Telepathy. If a creature communicates telepathically with the aboleth, the aboleth learns the creature's greatest desires if the aboleth can see the creature.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>The aboleth can take 3 legendary actions. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature's turn. The aboleth regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn. Detect. The aboleth makes a Perception check. Tail Swipe. The aboleth makes one tail attack. Psychic Drain (2 Actions). One creature charmed by the aboleth takes 10 (3d6) psychic damage, and the aboleth regains hit points equal to the damage the creature takes.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Multiattack. The aboleth makes three tentacle attacks.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>9</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Tentacle: Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (2d6 + 5) bludgeoning damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw or become Diseased. The disease has no effect for 1 minute and can be removed by any magic that cures disease. After 1 minute, the diseased creature's skin becomes translucent and slimy, the creature can't regain Hit Points unless it is Underwater, and the disease can be removed only by heal or another disease-curing spell of 6th level or higher. When the creature is outside a body of water, it takes 6 (1d12) acid damage every 10 minutes unless moisture is applied to the skin before 10 minutes have passed.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>2</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>5</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Tail: Melee Weapon Attack: +9 to hit, reach 10 ft. one target. Hit: 15 (3d6 + 5) bludgeoning damage.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>3</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>6</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>5</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>Enslave (3/day): The aboleth targets one creature it can see within 30 ft. of it. The target must succeed on a DC 14 Wisdom saving throw or be magically Charmed by the aboleth until the aboleth dies or until it is on a different plane of existence from the target. The Charmed target is under the aboleth's control and can't take Reactions, and the aboleth and the target can communicate telepathically with each other over any distance. Whenever the Charmed target takes damage, the target can repeat the saving throw. On a success, the Effect ends. No more than once every 24 hours, the target can also repeat the saving throw when it is at least 1 mile away from the aboleth.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Deva</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>LG</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>17</AC>
        <HP>136 (16d8 +64).</HP>
        <SPEED>30ft. fly 90ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Medium</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>1.8m</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>90k.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>18</STR>
        <STRMOD>+4</STRMOD>
        <DEX>18</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+4</DEXMOD>
        <CON>18</CON>
        <CONMOD>+4</CONMOD>
        <INT>17</INT>
        <INTMOD>+3</INTMOD>
        <WIS>20</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+5</WISMOD>
        <CHR>20</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>+5</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>Insight +9, Perception +9</SKILL>
        <SENSES>Darkvision 120 Ft., passive Perception 19</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>10 (5,900 XP).</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Angelic Weapons. The deva's weapon attacks are magical. When the deva hits with any weapon, the weapon deals an extra 4d8 radiant damage (included in the attack).</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Innate Spellcasting. The deva's spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 17). The deva can innately cast the following spells, requiring only verbal components: At will: detect evil and good 1/day each: commune, raise dead</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>Magic Resistance. The deva has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Multiattack. The deva makes two melee attacks.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>8</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Mace. Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: (1d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage plus (4d8)radiant damage.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>1</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>4</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Healing Touch (3/Day). The deva touches another creature. The target magically regains 20 (4d8 + 2) hit points and is freed from any curse, disease, poison, blindness, or deafness.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>4</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>8</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>2</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>Change Shape. The deva magically polymorphs into a humanoid or beast that has a challenge rating equal to or less than its own, or back into its true form. It reverts to its true form if it dies. Any equipment it is wearing or carrying is absorbed or borne by the new form (the deva's choice). In a new form, the deva retains its game statistics and ability to speak, but its AC, movement modes, Strength, Dexterity, and special senses are replaced by those of the new form, and it gains any statistics and capabilities (except class features, legendary actions, and lair actions) that the new form has but that it lacks.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Planetar</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>LG</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>19</AC>
        <HP>200 (16d10 + 112).</HP>
        <SPEED>40ft. fly 120ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Large</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>2.6m</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>225kg.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>24</STR>
        <STRMOD>+7</STRMOD>
        <DEX>20</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+5</DEXMOD>
        <CON>24</CON>
        <CONMOD>+7</CONMOD>
        <INT>19</INT>
        <INTMOD>+4</INTMOD>
        <WIS>22</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+6</WISMOD>
        <CHR>25</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>+7</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>Perception +11.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>truesight 120 ft., passive Perception 21. telepathy 120ft.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>16 (15.000XP).</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Angelic Weapons: The planetar's weapon attacks are magical. When the planetar hits with any weapon, the weapon deals an extra 5d8 radiant damage (included in the attack).</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Divine Awareness: The planetar knows if it hears a lie.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>Innate Spellcasting: The planetar's Spellcasting Ability is Charisma (spell save DC 20). The planetar can innately cast the following Spells, requiring no material components: At will: Detect Evil and Good, Invisibility (self only)</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>Magic Resistance: The planetar has advantage on Saving Throws against Spells and other magical Effects.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Multiattack: The planetar makes two Melee Attacks.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>12</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Greatsword: Melee Weapon Attack: +12 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 21 (4d6 + 7) slashing damage plus 22 (5d8) radiant damage.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>4</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>7</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Healing Touch (4/Day): The planetar touches another creature. The target magically regains 30 (6d8 + 3) Hit Points and is freed from any curse, disease, poison, blindness, or deafness.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>6</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>8</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>3</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>Spell: 3/day each: Blade Barrier, Dispel Evil and Good, Flame Strike, Raise Dead.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>Spell: 1/day each: Commune, Control Weather, Insect Plague.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Solar</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>LG</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>21</AC>
        <HP>243 (18d10 + 144).</HP>
        <SPEED>50ft. fly 150ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Large</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>3m.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>230kg.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>26</STR>
        <STRMOD>+8</STRMOD>
        <DEX>22</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+6</DEXMOD>
        <CON>26</CON>
        <CONMOD>+8</CONMOD>
        <INT>25</INT>
        <INTMOD>+7</INTMOD>
        <WIS>25</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+7</WISMOD>
        <CHR>30</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>+10</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>Perception +14.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>truesight 120ft., passive Perception 24. Telepathy 120ft.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>21 (33.000)XP.</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Angelic Weapons. The solar's weapon attacks are magical. When the solar hits with any weapon, the weapon deals an extra 6d8 radiant damage (included in the attack). Divine Awareness. The solar knows if it hears a lie.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Innate Spellcasting. The solar's spell casting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 25). It can innately cast the following spells, requiring no material components: At will: detect evil and good, invisibility (self only) 3/day each: blade barrier, dispel evil and good, resurrection 1/day each: commune, control weather.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>Magic Resistance. The solar has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects. Legendary Actions: Solar can take 3 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature’s turn. Solar regains spent legendary actions at the start of their turn.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>Teleport.The solar magically teleports, along with any equipment it is wearing or carrying, up to 120 ft. to an unoccupied space it can see. Searing Burst (2 Actions).The solar emits magical, divine energy. Each creature of its choice in a 10 -foot radius must make a DC 23 Dexterity saving throw, taking 14 (4d6) fire damage plus 14 (4d6) radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Blinding Gaze (Costs 3 Actions).The solar targets one creature it can see within 30 ft. of it. If the target can see it, the target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be blinded until magic such as the lesser restoration spell removes the blindness.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Multiattack. The solar makes two greatsword attacks.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>15</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Greatsword. Melee Weapon Attack: +15 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: (4d6 + 8) slashing damage plus (6d8)radiant damage. </ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>4</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>8</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Slaying Longbow. Ranged Weapon Attack: +13 to hit, reach 150/600 ft., one target. Hit: (2d8 + 6) piercing damage plus (6d8)radiant damage. If the target is a creature that has 100 hit points or fewer, it must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or die</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>2</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>8</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>6</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>Flying Sword. The solar releases its greatsword to hover magically in an unoccupied space within 5 ft. of it. If the solar can see the sword, the solar can mentally command it as a bonus action to fly up to 50 ft. and either make one attack against a target or return to the solar's hands. If the hovering sword is targeted by any effect, the solar is considered to be holding it. The hovering sword falls if the solar dies.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>Healing Touch (4/Day). The solar touches another creature. The target magically regains 40 (8d8 + 4) hit points and is freed from any curse, disease, poison, blindness, or deafness.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>8</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>8</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>4</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Animated Armor</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>Unaligned</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>18</AC>
        <HP>33 (6d8+6).</HP>
        <SPEED>25ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Medium</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>1.7m</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>35kg.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>14</STR>
        <STRMOD>+2</STRMOD>
        <DEX>11</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>0</DEXMOD>
        <CON>13</CON>
        <CONMOD>+1</CONMOD>
        <INT>1</INT>
        <INTMOD>-5 </INTMOD>
        <WIS>3</WIS>
        <WISMOD>-4 </WISMOD>
        <CHR>1</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>-5 </CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>blindsight 60ft. (blind beyond this radius. Passive Perception 6.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>1 (200XP)</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Antimagic Susceptibility: The armor is Incapacitated while in the area of an Antimagic Field. If targeted by Dispel Magic, the armor must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against the caster's spell save DC or fall Unconscious for 1 minute.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>False Appearance: While the armor remains motionless, it is indistinguishable from a normal suit of armor.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Multiattack: The armor makes two Melee Attacks.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>4</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Slam: Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) bludgeoning damage.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>1</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>2</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>.</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>.</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>.</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Flying Sword</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>Unaligned</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>17</AC>
        <HP>17 (5d6).</HP>
        <SPEED>0ft. fly 50ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Small</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>1mt.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>5kg.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>14</STR>
        <STRMOD>+2</STRMOD>
        <DEX>11</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>0</DEXMOD>
        <CON>13</CON>
        <CONMOD>+1</CONMOD>
        <INT>1</INT>
        <INTMOD>-5 </INTMOD>
        <WIS>3</WIS>
        <WISMOD>-4 </WISMOD>
        <CHR>1</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>-5 </CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>Blindsight 60 Ft. (Blind Beyond This Radius), passive Perception 6.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>1 (200XP).</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Antimagic Susceptibility. The armor is incapacitated while in the area of an antimagic field. If targeted by dispel magic, the armor must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against the caster's spell save DC or fall unconscious for 1 minute.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>False Appearance. While the armor remains motionless, it is indistinguishable from a normal suit of armor.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Multiattack. The armor makes two melee attacks.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>4</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Slam. Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: (1d6 + 2) bludgeoning damage. </ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>1</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>2</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>.</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>.</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>.</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Rug of Smothering</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>Unaligned</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>12</AC>
        <HP>33 (6d10).</HP>
        <SPEED>10ft</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Large</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>2mts.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>10kg</WEIGHT>
        <STR>17</STR>
        <STRMOD>+3</STRMOD>
        <DEX>14</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+2</DEXMOD>
        <CON>10</CON>
        <CONMOD>0</CONMOD>
        <INT>1</INT>
        <INTMOD>-5 </INTMOD>
        <WIS>3</WIS>
        <WISMOD>-4 </WISMOD>
        <CHR>1</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>-5 </CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>Blindsight 60 Ft. (Blind Beyond This Radius), passive Perception 6.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>2 (450XP).</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Antimagic Susceptibility. The rug is incapacitated while in the area of an antimagic field. If targeted by dispel magic, the rug must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against the caster's spell save DC or fall unconscious for 1 minute.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Damage Transfer. While it is grappling a creature, the rug takes only half the damage dealt to it, and the creature grappled by the rug takes the other half.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>False Appearance. While the rug remains motionless, it is indistinguishable from a normal rug.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>5</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Smother. Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one medium or smaller creature. bludgeoning damage On Hit: The creature is grappled escape DC 13. Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, blinded, and at risk of suffocating, and the rug can't smother another target. In addition, at the start of each of the target's turns, the target takes 10 (2d6 + 3) bludgeoning damage.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>2</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>3</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>.</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>.</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>.</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Ankheg</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>Unaligned</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>14</AC>
        <HP>39 (6d10+6).</HP>
        <SPEED>30ft. burrow 10ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Large</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>3mts.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>370kg.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>17</STR>
        <STRMOD>+3</STRMOD>
        <DEX>11</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>0</DEXMOD>
        <CON>13</CON>
        <CONMOD>+1</CONMOD>
        <INT>1</INT>
        <INTMOD>-5 </INTMOD>
        <WIS>13</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+1</WISMOD>
        <CHR>6</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>-2 </CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>Darkvision 60 Ft., Tremorsense 60 Ft., passive Perception 11</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>2 (450XP).</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>5</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Bite. Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: (2d6 + 3) slashing damage plus (1d6)acid damage. If the target is a Large or smaller creature, it is grappled (escape DC 13). Until this grapple ends, the ankheg can bite only the grappled creature and has advantage on attack rolls to do so</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>3</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>3</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Acid Spray (Recharge 6). The ankheg spits acid in a line that is 30 ft. long and 5 ft. wide, provided that it has no creature grappled. Each creature in that line must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking 10 (3d6) acid damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>3</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>6</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>0</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Azer</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>LN</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>17</AC>
        <HP>39 (6d8+12).</HP>
        <SPEED>30ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Medium</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>1.5mts</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>95kg.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>17</STR>
        <STRMOD>+3</STRMOD>
        <DEX>12</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+1</DEXMOD>
        <CON>15</CON>
        <CONMOD>+2</CONMOD>
        <INT>12</INT>
        <INTMOD>+1</INTMOD>
        <WIS>13</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+1</WISMOD>
        <CHR>10</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>0</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>passive Perception 11</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>2 (450 XP).</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Heated Body. A creature that touches the azer or hits it with a melee attack while within 5 ft. of it takes 5 (1d10) fire damage.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Heated Weapons. When the azer hits with a metal melee weapon, it deals an extra 3 (1d6) fire damage (included in the attack).</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>Illumination. The azer sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 ft..</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>5</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Warhammer. Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: (1d10 + 3) bludgeoning damage plus (1d6)fire damage. two handed</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>1</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>10</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>3</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Warhammer. Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: (1d8 + 3) bludgeoning damage plus (1d6)fire damage. one handed</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>1</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>8</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>3</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Banshee</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>CE</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>12</AC>
        <HP>58 (13d8).</HP>
        <SPEED>0ft.fly 40ft</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Medium</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>1.7mts</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>???</WEIGHT>
        <STR>1</STR>
        <STRMOD>-5 </STRMOD>
        <DEX>14</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+2</DEXMOD>
        <CON>10</CON>
        <CONMOD>0</CONMOD>
        <INT>12</INT>
        <INTMOD>+1</INTMOD>
        <WIS>11</WIS>
        <WISMOD>0</WISMOD>
        <CHR>17</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>+3</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 10.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>4 (1100XP).</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Detect Life. The banshee can magically sense the presence of living creatures up to 5 miles away. She knows the general direction they're in but not their exact locations.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Incorporeal Movement. The banshee can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. She takes 5 (1d10) force damage if she ends her turn inside an object.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>4</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Corrupting Touch. Melee Spell Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 12 (3d6 + 2) necrotic damage.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>3</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>2</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Horrifying Visage. Each non-undead creature within 60 feet of the banshee that can see her must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. A frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, with disadvantage if the banshee is within line of sight, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a target's saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the target is immune to the banshee's Horrifying Visage for the next 24 hours.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>.</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>.</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>.</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>Wail (1/Day). The banshee releases a mournful wail, provided that she isn't in sunlight. This wail has no effect on constructs and undead . All other creatures within 30 feet of her that can hear her must  make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, a creature drops to 0 hit points. On a success, a creature takes 10 (3d6) psychic damage.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>3</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>6</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>0</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Basilisk</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>Unaligned</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>15</AC>
        <HP>52 (8d8+16)</HP>
        <SPEED>20ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Medium</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>4mts.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>140kg.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>16</STR>
        <STRMOD>+3</STRMOD>
        <DEX>8</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>-1 </DEXMOD>
        <CON>15</CON>
        <CONMOD>+2</CONMOD>
        <INT>2</INT>
        <INTMOD>-4 </INTMOD>
        <WIS>8</WIS>
        <WISMOD>-1 </WISMOD>
        <CHR>7</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>-2 </CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>Darkvision 60 Ft., passive Perception 9</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>3 (700 XP).</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Petrifying Gaze. If a creature starts its turn within 30 ft. of the basilisk and the two of them can see each other, the basilisk can force the creature to make a DC 12 Constitution saving throw if the basilisk isn't incapacitated. On a failed save, the creature magically begins to turn to stone and is restrained. It must repeat the saving throw at the end of its next turn. On a success, the effect ends. On a failure, the creature is petrified until freed by the greater restoration spell or other magic.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>A creature that isn't surprised can avert its eyes to avoid the saving throw at the start of its turn. If it does so, it can't see the basilisk until the start of its next turn, when it can avert its eyes again. If it looks at the basilisk in the meantime, it must immediately make the save.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>If the basilisk sees its reflection within 30 ft. of it in bright light, it mistakes itself for a rival and targets itself with its gaze.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>5</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Bite. Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: (2d6 + 3) piercing damage plus (2d6)poison damage. </ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>4</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>3</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>.</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>.</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>.</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Behir</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>NE</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>17</AC>
        <HP>168 (16d12+64)</HP>
        <SPEED>50ft. climb 40ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Huge</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>12mts</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>1800kg</WEIGHT>
        <STR>23</STR>
        <STRMOD>+6</STRMOD>
        <DEX>16</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+3</DEXMOD>
        <CON>18</CON>
        <CONMOD>+4</CONMOD>
        <INT>7</INT>
        <INTMOD>-2 </INTMOD>
        <WIS>14</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+2</WISMOD>
        <CHR>12</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>+1</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>Perception +6, Stealth +7</SKILL>
        <SENSES>Darkvision 90 Ft., passive Perception 16</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>11 (7,200 XP)</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>Swallow. The behir makes one bite attack against a Medium or smaller target it is grappling. If the attack hits, the target is also swallowed, and the grapple ends. While swallowed, the target is blinded and restrained, it has total cover against attacks and other effects outside the behir, and it takes 21 (6d6) acid damage at the start of each of the behir's turns. A behir can have only one creature swallowed at a time. If the behir takes 30 damage or more on a single turn from the swallowed creature, the behir must succeed on a DC 14 Constitution saving throw at the end of that turn or regurgitate the creature, which falls prone in a space within 10 ft. of the behir. If the behir dies, a swallowed creature is no longer restrained by it and can escape from the corpse by using 15 ft. of movement, exiting prone.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Multiattack. The behir makes two attacks: one with its bite and one to constrict.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>10</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Bite. Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: (3d10 + 6) piercing damage.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>3</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>10</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>6</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Constrict. Melee Weapon Attack: +10 to hit, reach 5 ft., one large or smaller creature. Hit: (2d10 + 6) bludgeoning damage plus (2d10 + 6)slashing damage. The target is grappled (escape DC 16) if the behir isn't already constricting a creature, and the target is restrained until this grapple ends</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>4</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>10</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>12</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>Lightning Breath (Recharge 5-6). The behir exhales a line of lightning that is 20 ft. long and 5 ft. wide. Each creature in that line must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw, taking 66 (12d10) lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>12</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>10</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>0</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>6</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>6</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>0</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Beholder</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>LE</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>18</AC>
        <HP>180 (19d10+76)</HP>
        <SPEED>0ft. hovering 20ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Large</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>2.4mts</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>150kg</WEIGHT>
        <STR>10</STR>
        <STRMOD>0</STRMOD>
        <DEX>14</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+2</DEXMOD>
        <CON>18</CON>
        <CONMOD>+4</CONMOD>
        <INT>17</INT>
        <INTMOD>+3</INTMOD>
        <WIS>15</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+2</WISMOD>
        <CHR>17</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>+3</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>Perception +12</SKILL>
        <SENSES>darkvision 120ft. passive Perception 22.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>13 (10.000 XP)</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Antimagic Cone. The beholder's central eye creates an area of antimagic, as in the antimagic field spell, in a 150-foot cone. At the start of each of its turns, the beholder decides which way the cone faces and whether the cone is active. The area works against the beholder's own eye rays. </POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Paralyzing Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Sleep Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or fall asleep and remain unconscious for 1 minute. The target awakens if it takes damage or another creature takes an action to wake it. This ray has no effect on constructs and undead.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>Charm Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by the beholder for 1 hour, or until the beholder harms the creature. Fear Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>Slowing Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the target's speed is halved for 1 minute. In addition, the creature can't take reactions, and it can take either an action or a bonus action on its turn, not both. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect 0n itself on a success.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Eye Rays. The beholder shoots three of the following magical eye rays at random (reroll duplicates), choosing one to three targets it can see within 120 feet of it. The beholder can take legendary actions: using a random eye ray.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>5</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Enervation Ray. The targeted creature must  make a DC 16 Constitution saving throw, taking 36 (8d8) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>8</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>8</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>0</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Disintegration Ray. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw or take 45 (10d8) force damage. If this damage reduces the creature to 0 hit points, its  body becomes a pile of fine gray dust. If the target is a Large or smaller non magical object or creation of magical force, it is disintegrated without a saving throw. If the target is a Huge or larger object or creation of magical force, this ray disintegrates a 10-foot cube of it.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>10</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>8</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>0</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>Death Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw or take 55 (10d10) necrotic damage. The target dies if the ray reduces it to 0 hit points. Telekinetic Ray. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 16 Strength saving throw or the beholder moves it up to 30 feet in any direction. It is restrained by the ray's telekinetic grip until the start of the beholder's next turn or until the beholder is incapacitated. If the target is an object weighing 300 pounds or less that isn't being worn or carried, it is moved up to 30 feet in any direction. The beholder can also exert fine control on objects with this ray, such as manipulating a simple tool or opening a door or a container.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>10</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>10</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>0</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>Petrification Ray. The targeted creature must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature begins to turn to stone and is restrained. It must  repeat the saving throw at the end of its next turn. On a success, the effect ends. On a failure, the creature is  petrified until freed by the greater rest.oration spell or other magic. Bite. Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 14 (4d6) piercing damage.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>4</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>6</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>0</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Death Tyrant</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>LE</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>19</AC>
        <HP>187 (25d10+50)</HP>
        <SPEED>0ft. hovering 20ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Large</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>2.4mts</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>150kg</WEIGHT>
        <STR>10</STR>
        <STRMOD>0</STRMOD>
        <DEX>14</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+2</DEXMOD>
        <CON>14</CON>
        <CONMOD>+2</CONMOD>
        <INT>19</INT>
        <INTMOD>+4</INTMOD>
        <WIS>15</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+2</WISMOD>
        <CHR>19</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>+4</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>Perception +12</SKILL>
        <SENSES>darkvision 120ft. passive Perception 22.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>14 (11.500 XP)</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Negative Energy Cone. The death tyrant's central eye emits an invisible, magical 150-foot cone of negative energy. At the start of each of its turns, the tyrant decides which way the cone faces and whether the cone is active. Any creature in that area can't regain hit points. Any humanoid that dies there becomes a zombie under the tyrant's command. The dead humanoid retains its place in the initiative order and animates at the start of its next turn, provided that its body hasn't been completely destroyed.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Paralyzing Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Sleep Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw or fall asleep and remain unconscious for 1 minute. The target awakens if it takes damage or another creature takes an action to wake it. This ray has no effect on constructs and undead.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>Charm Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by the beholder for 1 hour, or until the beholder harms the creature. Fear Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>Slowing Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the target's speed is halved for 1 minute. In addition, the creature can't take reactions, and it can take either an action or a bonus action on its turn, not both. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect 0n itself on a success.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Eye Rays. The beholder shoots three of the following magical eye rays at random (reroll duplicates), choosing one to three targets it can see within 120 feet of it. The beholder can take legendary actions: using a random eye ray.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>5</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Enervation Ray. The targeted creature must  make a DC 17 Constitution saving throw, taking 36 (8d8) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>8</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>8</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>0</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Disintegration Ray. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw or take 45 (10d8) force damage. If this damage reduces the creature to 0 hit points, its  body becomes a pile of fine gray dust. If the target is a Large or smaller non magical object or creation of magical force, it is disintegrated without a saving throw. If the target is a Huge or larger object or creation of magical force, this ray disintegrates a 10-foot cube of it.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>10</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>8</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>0</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>Death Ray. The targeted creature must succeed on a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw or take 55 (10d10) necrotic damage. The target dies if the ray reduces it to 0 hit points. Telekinetic Ray. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 16 Strength saving throw or the beholder moves it up to 30 feet in any direction. It is restrained by the ray's telekinetic grip until the start of the beholder's next turn or until the beholder is incapacitated. If the target is an object weighing 300 pounds or less that isn't being worn or carried, it is moved up to 30 feet in any direction. The beholder can also exert fine control on objects with this ray, such as manipulating a simple tool or opening a door or a container.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>10</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>10</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>0</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>Petrification Ray. The targeted creature must make a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature begins to turn to stone and is restrained. It must  repeat the saving throw at the end of its next turn. On a success, the effect ends. On a failure, the creature is  petrified until freed by the greater rest.oration spell or other magic. Bite. Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 14 (4d6) piercing damage.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>4</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>6</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>0</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>Spectator</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>LN</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>14</AC>
        <HP>39 (6d8+12)</HP>
        <SPEED>0ft. hover 30ft.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>Medium</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>1.7mts</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>70kg</WEIGHT>
        <STR>8</STR>
        <STRMOD>-1 </STRMOD>
        <DEX>14</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>+2</DEXMOD>
        <CON>14</CON>
        <CONMOD>+2</CONMOD>
        <INT>13</INT>
        <INTMOD>+1</INTMOD>
        <WIS>14</WIS>
        <WISMOD>+2</WISMOD>
        <CHR>11</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>0</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>Perception +6</SKILL>
        <SENSES>Darkvision 120 ft., Passive Perception 16</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>3 (700 XP)</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>Confusion Ray. The target must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw, or it can’t take reactions until the end of its next turn. On its turn, the target can’t move, and it uses its action to make a melee or ranged attack against a randomly determined creature within range. If the target can’t attack, it does nothing on its turn.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>Paralyzing Ray. The target must succeed on a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>Create Food and Water. The spectator magically creates enough food and water to sustain itself for 24 hours.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>Spell Reflection. If the spectator makes a successful saving throw against a spell, or a spell attack misses it, the spectator can choose another creature (including the spellcaster) it can see within 30 feet of it. The spell targets the chosen creature instead of the spectator. If the spell forced a saving throw, the chosen creature makes its own save. If the spell was an attack, the attack roll is rerolled against the chosen creature.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>Eye Rays. The spectator shoots up to two of the following magical eye rays at one or two creatures it can see within 90 feet of it. It can use each ray only once on a turn.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>1</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>Bite. Melee Weapon Attack: +1 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2 (1d6 − 1) piercing damage.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>1</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>6</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>-1</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>Fear Ray. The target must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, with disadvantage if the spectator is visible to the target, ending the effect on itself on a success.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>.</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>.</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>.</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>Wounding Ray. The target must make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw, taking 16 (3d10) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>3</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>10</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>0</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>BLIGHTS</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>.</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>.</AC>
        <HP>.</HP>
        <SPEED>.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>.</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>.</STR>
        <STRMOD>.</STRMOD>
        <DEX>.</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>.</DEXMOD>
        <CON>.</CON>
        <CONMOD>.</CONMOD>
        <INT>.</INT>
        <INTMOD>.</INTMOD>
        <WIS>.</WIS>
        <WISMOD>.</WISMOD>
        <CHR>.</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>.</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>.</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>.</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>.</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>.</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>.</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>.</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>.</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>.</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>.</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>.</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>.</AC>
        <HP>.</HP>
        <SPEED>.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>.</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>.</STR>
        <STRMOD>.</STRMOD>
        <DEX>.</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>.</DEXMOD>
        <CON>.</CON>
        <CONMOD>.</CONMOD>
        <INT>.</INT>
        <INTMOD>.</INTMOD>
        <WIS>.</WIS>
        <WISMOD>.</WISMOD>
        <CHR>.</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>.</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>.</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>.</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>.</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>.</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>.</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>.</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>.</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>.</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
    <BICHO>
        <NAME>.</NAME>
        <ALIGNMENT>.</ALIGNMENT>
        <AC>.</AC>
        <HP>.</HP>
        <SPEED>.</SPEED>
        <SIZE>.</SIZE>
        <HEIGHT>.</HEIGHT>
        <WEIGHT>.</WEIGHT>
        <STR>.</STR>
        <STRMOD>.</STRMOD>
        <DEX>.</DEX>
        <DEXMOD>.</DEXMOD>
        <CON>.</CON>
        <CONMOD>.</CONMOD>
        <INT>.</INT>
        <INTMOD>.</INTMOD>
        <WIS>.</WIS>
        <WISMOD>.</WISMOD>
        <CHR>.</CHR>
        <CHRMOD>.</CHRMOD>
        <SKILL>.</SKILL>
        <SENSES>.</SENSES>
        <CHALLENGE>.</CHALLENGE>
        <POWER_1>.</POWER_1>
        <POWER_2>.</POWER_2>
        <POWER_3>.</POWER_3>
        <POWER_4>.</POWER_4>
        <ACTION_DES>.</ACTION_DES>
        <ATTACK>.</ATTACK>
        <ACTION_1>.</ACTION_1>
        <ACTIONDADOS_1>.</ACTIONDADOS_1>
        <ACTIONVALOR_1>.</ACTIONVALOR_1>
        <ACTIONMODI_1>.</ACTIONMODI_1>
        <ACTION_2>.</ACTION_2>
        <ACTIONDADOS_2>.</ACTIONDADOS_2>
        <ACTIONVALOR_2>.</ACTIONVALOR_2>
        <ACTIONMODI_2>.</ACTIONMODI_2>
        <ACTION_3>.</ACTION_3>
        <ACTIONDADOS_3>.</ACTIONDADOS_3>
        <ACTIONVALOR_3>.</ACTIONVALOR_3>
        <ACTIONMODI_3>.</ACTIONMODI_3>
        <ACTION_4>.</ACTION_4>
        <ACTIONDADOS_4>.</ACTIONDADOS_4>
        <ACTIONVALOR_4>.</ACTIONVALOR_4>
        <ACTIONMODI_4>.</ACTIONMODI_4>
    </BICHO>
</MOSTROS>